Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Publications and Ephemera MC.334
New York University Archives
- RG 25.0. College of Dentistry, 1867-ongoing
  - Access, 1980 (Box 221, Folder 6)
  - The Arouser (Alpha Omega Fraternity), 1986-1988 (Box 221, Folder 7)
  - Aspirations, 1996-1997 (Box 221, Folder 8)
  - The Baseplate, 1949 (Box 221, Folder 9)
  - Century Club Newsletter, 1965-1968 (Box 222, Folder 1)
  - Clinical Affairs, 1994 (Box 222, Folder 2)
  - College of Dentistry Facebook, May 2014-May 2015
    Facebook page of NYU College of Dentistry. Includes posts on research news, new Dentistry building, faculty achievements, health screening announcements, and other events.
  - College of Dentistry Pediatric Dentistry Alumni Association Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the NYU College of Dentistry Pediatric Dental Alumni Association. Contains alumni news and event announcements.
  - College of Dentistry Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter feed for the NYU College of Dentistry. Tweets include research days, admissions, dental hygiene, conferences, faculty and student achievements, dental education, and other event and news announcements.
  - The Dean's Memorandum, 1976-1978 (Box 222, Folder 3-4)
  - Dental Alumni Issues and Events, 1980-1985 (Box 222, Folder 5)
  - Dental Center Library Newsletter, 1983-1987 (Box 222, Folder 6-8, Box 223, Folder 1)
  - Dental Center News / The News, 1970-1974 (Box 165, Folder 11)
  - Dental Center Newsletter, 1978-1987 (Box 223, Folder 2-5)
  - Dental Items of Interest, 1937 (Box 223, Folder 6)
  - Dental News Center, 1981-1987 (Box 243, Folder 11)
  - Dental Times, 1965 (Box 243, Folder 11)
  - Dental Update, 1991 (Box 223, Folder 7)
  - Dentanews, June 1950 (Box 223, Folder 8)
  - Developments, 2002 (Box 223, Folder 9)
  - Explorer, 1958-1969 (Box 244, Folder 1-14)
  - Explorer, 1970-1980 (Box 245, Folder 1-11)
  - Explorer, 1981-1994 (Box 246, Folder 1-7)
  - Explorer, 1996-1997 (Box 224, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Forum, May 1969-March 1970 (Box 224, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Newsletter, 1979-1981 (Box 224, Folder 3)
  - Filling In, 1991 (Box 224, Folder 4)
  - Forum, 1974-1976 (Box 246, Folder 8)
  - The Freshman Dental Review, 1953 (Box 224, Folder 5)
  - Global Health Nexus, 1999-2003 (Box 224, Folder 6-9, Box 225, Folder 1-4)
  - Global Health Nexus, May 2021-ongoing
    Global Health Nexus was first published in 1999 and is a publication of NYU Dentistry for dentists, prospective and current NYU dental students, alumni, faculty, and staff, nurses, public health professionals, national and international educators and students, heads of major corporations, foundations, community leaders, and local, state, and federal legislators. The publication spotlights dental research, recruitment, grants and philanthropy, NYU staff and students in the news, awards, promotions, obituaries, international updates, messages from the dean, and strategic planning.
  - Inci-Dentals, 1973-1974 (Box 225, Folder 5)
  - Information Bulletin of the Dental Research Society, 1951 (Box 225, Folder 6)
  - Interface, 2009 (Box 246, Folder 8)
  - Keeping in Touch, 1997-1998 (Box 225, Folder 7)
  - The Laboratory Technician, 1933, 1936 (Box 226, Folder 1)
  - Linhart Continuing Dental Education Program Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Linhart Continuing Dental Education Program. Includes courses, event announcements, and education workshops.
  - List of Journals and Serials Alphabetically Arranged, 1988, 1995-1996 (Box 226, Folder 2)
  - The Mirror, 1987 (Box 226, Folder 3)
  - New York University Dental Bulletin, 1942-1945 (Box 226, Folder 4-6)
  - New York University Dental Journal / New York University Journal of Dentistry, 1942-1950 (Box 227, Folder 1-4, Box 228, Box 229, Folder 1-5)
  - New York University Journal of Dentistry, 1951-1963 (Box 230, Folder 1-5, Box 231, Folder 1-6, Box 232, Folder 1-8)
  - New York University Journal of Dentistry, 1963-1969 (Box 233, Folder 1-3)
  - The NYU Dental News / The Dental News, 1937-1944 (Box 243, Folder 1-10)
  - NYUC Dental Hygiene Program Newsletter, 1998-1999 (Box 233, Folder 4)
  - The Odontologist, 1905 (Box 233, Folder 5)
  - Omicron Kappa Upsilon Omega Chapter Newsletter, 1969, 1977, 2000-2001 (Box 233, Folder 6)
  - Perspectives, 1977 (Box 233, Folder 7)
  - Pillars of Excellence, 1997 (Box 233, Folder 8)
  - The Record, 1888-1899 (Box 234, Folder 1-2)
  - Research Activities at NYUCD, 1985-1990 (Box 234, Folder 3-4)
  - Research Newsletter, 1988-1998 (Box 234, Folder 5)
  - The Triturator, 1978-1981 (Box 234, Folder 6, Box 235, Folder 1-2)
  - Update, 1988 (Box 235, Folder 3)
  - Varsity Journal, 1921 (Box 235, Folder 4)
  - The Waldman Letter, 1997 (Box 235, Folder 5)
  - Promotional Material and Event Ephemera, 1908-2010 (Box 235, Folder 6-13, Box 236, Folder 1-12)
  - Promotional Material and Event Ephemera -- Posters, 1960s-1970s (Box 167, Folder 9)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- 50th Anniversary of the College of Dentistry, 1916 (Box 237, Folder 1)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- 75th Anniversary of the College of Dentistry, 1941-1942 (Box 237, Folder 2-3)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- 100th Anniversary of the College of Dentistry, 1964-1967 (Box 237, Folder 4-5)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- 125th Anniversary of the College of Dentistry, 1991 (Box 237, Folder 6)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Alpha Omega Fraternity, 1986-1988 (Box 237, Folder 7)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Alumni Association Meetings and Events, 1889-1999 (Box 237, Folder 8-10, Box 238, Folder 1-5)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Alumni Day, 1923-1991 (Box 238, Folder 6-9, Box 239, Folder 1)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Class Reunions, 1916-1982 (Box 239, Folder 2-3)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Commencement, 1867-1914 (Box 239, Folder 4-7)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Dental Health Outreach, 1989 (Box 239, Folder 8)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- New York Odontological Society, 1886 (Box 239, Folder 9)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Parent's Association Annual Dinner, 1959-1982 (Box 239, Folder 10, Box 240, Folder 1-4)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Alphabetical Subject Files -- Press Releases, 1943-1965, 1984-1986 (Box 240, Folder 5-6)
- RG 25.1. Post-Graduate Division, 1941-1989
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1941-1989 (Box 240, Folder 7-9, Box 241, Folder 1-4)
- RG 25.2. David B. Kriser Dental Center, 1980-2004
  - Community, 1996-1998 (Box 241, Folder 5)
  - The Dean's Newsletter, 1989-1991 (Box 241, Folder 6)
  - Kriser Dental Center Newsletter / NYU Kriser Dental Center Faculty and Student News Briefs, 1987-1994 (Box 241, Folder 7)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1980-2004 (Box 241, Folder 8, Box 242, Folder 1-3)
- RG 25.4. Institute for Dental Research, 1954-1962
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1954-1962 (Box 242, Folder 4-5)
- RG 26.0. Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development, 1936-1938, 1982-1983, 2014-2015
  - Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for NYU Steinhardt. Posts on Steinhardt's 125th anniversary, performances, summer programs, images, admissions, alumni accomplishments, and other events.
  - Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter Feed of the Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development at New York University. Includes tweets on commencement, conferences, seminars, workshops, professional development, performances at the Provincetown Playhouse, education fairs, admissions, the NYU Symphony Orchestra, studies, NYC public schools, and other events.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1936-1938, 1982-1983 (Box 242, Folder 6-7)
- RG 26.1. Graduate Study Abroad / Office of Off-Campus Programs, 1964-2007
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1964-2007 (Box 242, Folder 8-13, Box 247, Folder 1-3)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Posters, 1980-1983, 2000 (Box 195, Folder 10)
- RG 26.2. Puerto Rico Residence Center, 1965-1982, undated
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1965-1982, undated (Box 247, Folder 4-6)
- RG 26.3. Institute for Developmental Studies, 1966-1976
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1966-1976 (Box 247, Folder 7)
- RG 26.4. Center for Human Relations Studies, circa 1975
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, circa 1975 (Box 247, Folder 8)
- RG 26.6. Hebrew Culture and Education, 1941-1979
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1941-1985 (Box 247, Folder 9, Box 248, Folder 1)
- RG 26.9. Higher Education Opportunity Program, 1973-1989, 2000s
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1973-1989, 2000s (Box 248, Folder 2-3)
- RG 26.11. Center for Music Performance / Department of Music and Performing Arts Professions, 1993-ongoing
  NYU Steinhardt's Department of Music and Performing Arts Professions was established in 1925, and has developed into a major research and practice center in music technology, music business, music composition, film scoring, music performance practices, performing arts therapies, and the performing arts-in-education.
  - ARTSPRAXIS, September 2021-ongoing
    The journal includes contributions from arts educators, therapists, arts agencies, arts administrators, funding bodies, arts scholars, and community artists from diverse settings. The journal emphasizes critical analysis of the arts in society. Affiliated with the NYU Steinhardt Program in Educational Theatre.
    ArtsPraxis was founded in 2003 by Dr. Philip Taylor following the NYU Forum on Arts Assessment. The journal facilitates dialogue between arts disciplines.
  - Calendar of Events, 2006-2019 (Box 248, Folder 4-7)
  - Department of Music and Performing Arts Professions Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Includes posts on student performances, alumni awards and performances, images from performances, and other events.
  - Revue Blog, May 2014-May 2020
    Revue is the blog for the Department of Music and Performing Arts Professions at Steinhardt. The blog contains posts on call for proposals and summaries of their journal ArtsPraxis, performance and audition announcements, alumni spotlights and updates, event announcements, speakers series descriptions, classroom activities, theater at the Provincetown Playhouse, and information about productions and theater associated with the program.
  - Revue Blog, May 2020-May 2021
  - Revue Newsletter, May 2014-May 2018
    Revue is the newsletter for the Department of Music and Performing Arts Professions at Steinhardt. It contains posts on call for proposals and summaries of their journal ArtsPraxis, performance and audition announcements, alumni spotlights and updates, event announcements, speakers series descriptions, classroom activities, theater at the Provincetown Playhouse, and information about productions and theater associated with the program. It dates back to 2003.
  - Square Notes, 1993-2004 (Box 248, Folder 8-9, Box 195, Folder 11-12)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1996-2014 (Box 249, Folder 1-3)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Posters, 2005-2006, 2010 (Box 195, Folder 13, Box 167, Folder 10)
- RG 26.12. National Arts Education Research Center, 1989
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1989 (Box 249, Folder 4)
- RG 26.13. Regional AIDS Education and Training Center / AIDS Mental Health Project, 1986-1996
  - HIV / AIDS Focus, 1995 (Box 249, Folder 5)
  - HIV / AIDS and Mental Hygiene, 1992-1996 (Box 249, Folder 6)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1986-1987 (Box 249, Folder 7-8)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Curriculum Guides, 1989-1995 (Box 249, Folder 9-10, Box 250, Folder 1-7, Box 251, Folder 1)
- RG 26.14. Department of Educational Theater, 1998-2007
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1998-2007 (Box 251, Folder 2)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Posters, 2006-2007 (Box 195, Folder 13)
- RG 26.15. Office of Education Research Services, 1968-1971
  - OERS Research Agenda, 1970-1971 (Box 251, Folder 3)
  - OERS Research and Training Review, 1969-1970 (Box 251, Folder 4)
  - OERS Review, 1968-1969 (Box 251, Folder 5)
- RG 26.16. Deafness Research and Training Center, 1970-1980
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1970-1980 (Box 251, Folder 6-7)
- RG 26.17. New Careers Development Center, 1968-1971
  - New Careers Newsletter, 1968-1971 (Box 251, Folder 8)
  - New Human Services, 1970-1971 (Box 252, Folder 1)
- RG 26.18. Metropolitan Center for Urban Education, 1982, 2002-2007
  - Metro Center News, 2002-2003 (Box 252, Folder 2)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1982, 2002-2007 (Box 252, Folder 3-4)
- RG 26.20. Graphic Communications Management and Technology, undated
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, undated (Box 252, Folder 5)
- RG 26.21. Institute for Education and Social Policy, 2004-2020
  Institute for Education and Social Policy (IESP) conducts non-partisan scientific research about U.S. education and related social policy issues to help inform educational institutions and policymakers about the effectiveness of instructional programs, the impact of school reform initiatives and the relationships between academic achievement, school finance and socio-economic and demographic factors such as poverty, ethnicity and immigration status.
  - Institute for Education and Social Policy Facebook, May 2014-May 2015
    Facebook page for the Institute for Education and Social Policy (IESP). Contains links to research reports, photographs from events, event listings, and features by and about Sean Corcoran.
  - Institute for Education and Social Policy News, May 2014-May 2020
    The website contains summaries of their research findings and reports, grant awards, conference reports, and news about and by Sean Corcoran.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 2004 (Box 252, Folder 6)
- RG 26.22. Department of Nutrition, Food Studies, and Public Health, 1980s, 2004-2007
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1980s, 2004-2007 (Box 252, Folder 7)
- RG 26.23. Department of Art and Art Professions, 2004-2008
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 2004 (Box 252, Folder 8)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Posters, 2007-2008 (Box 167, Folder 10)
- RG 26.24. Department of Teaching and Learning, 2005-2019
  - Steinhardt Department of Teaching and Learning News & Announcements, May 2014-April 2019
    Website highlighting news from the Steinhardt Department of Teaching and Learning. News topics include student and faculty awards, alumni spotlights, education policy, conference presentations, report findings, new teacher residency program (EMAT), Education Solutions Initiative, interviews, and events at Steinhardt.
  - Steinhardt Institute for Higher Education Policy News, May 2014-April 2019
    The news pages of the website provide coverage of the Institute's events, coverage from conferences attended by Steinhardt-affiliated individuals, highlights from Steinhardt publications, media coverage related to the Institute, and activities related to Teboho Moja, Stella Flores, and Ann Marcus. Topics researched by the Institute include the affects of globalization on higher education; the influence of collegiate conditions, educational practices, and student experiences on student learning and development; and the stratification of college opportunity for racial and ethnic minorities.
    The Steinhardt Institute for Higher Education Policy focuses on research and dialogue related to challenges within colleges and universities.
  - Steinhardt School of Culture, Education, and Human Development Newsletters, May 2014-May 2019
    Newsletter providing news about what is happening within the NYU Steinhardt community. It includes news about students working within the community and studying abroad, the academic research of our faculty, and alumni news. Dates back to 2013.
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 2005 (Box 252, Folder 9)
- RG 26.25. Department of Occupational Therapy, 1970-2007
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1970-2007 (Box 252, Folder 10)
- RG 26.28. Office of Special Programs, 1990-2012
  - At a Glance, 2012 (Box 252, Folder 11)
  - Events, 2003 (Box 252, Folder 12)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1990-2008 (Box 252, Folder 13, Box 253, Folder 3-10, Box 254, Folder 1-7)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Steinhardt Conference on Beat Poets, 1993-1995 (Box 252, Folder 14, Box 253, Folder 1-2)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera -- Posters, 2005 (Box 195, Folder 13)
- RG 26.31. Head Start at NYU, 1997
  - Events, November 1997 (Box 254, Folder 8)
- RG 26.33. Community College Transfer Opportunity Program (NYUCCTOP), undated
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, undated (Box 254, Folder 9)
- RG 26.38. Research Alliance for New York City Schools, 2014-2015, 2024-ongoing
  The Research Alliance conducts studies and research on topics related to New York City's public schools.
  - Research Alliance for New York City Schools Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Research Alliance for New York City Schools, which is housed in the Steinhardt School. The Facebook page contains links to their research projects, job postings, event listings and recaps, promotion announcements, and the Alliance in the media. Much of the focus on the pages from 2013-2014 focused on their research related to the Expanded Success Initiative.
  - Research Alliance for New York City Schools Twitter, May 2014-August 2015
    Twitter feed for the Research Alliance for New York City Schools, which is housed in the Steinhardt School. The Twitter feed mostly contains links to news articles and reports related to to New York City schools, as well as outreach related to the NYC School Survey.
  - Research Alliance for New York City Schools Publications, April 2024-ongoing
    The Research Alliance for New York City Schools publications feature studies and other research on New York City public schools. The earliest research dates from 2007.
- RG 26.39. Center for Practice and Research at the Intersection of Information, Society, and Methodology (PRIISM), 2015-2018
  - Center for Practice and Research at the Intersection of Information, Society, and Methodology (PRIISM) News, May 2015-May 2018
    News page for the Center for Practice and Research at the Intersection of Information, Society, and Methodology (formerly known as the Center for the Promotion of Research Involving Innovative Statistical Methodology). Contains course descriptions related to applied statistical methods.
- RG 26.40. Department of Physical Therapy, 2014-2018
  - Department of Physical Therapy Annual Newsletter, May 2014-May 2018
    PDFs of the Department of Physical Therapy's Annual Newsletter. It contains alumni profiles and updates, faculty milestones, student honors, donor acknowledgements, obituaries, and other news. The newsletter dates back to 2004.
- RG 26.42. Department of Media, Culture, and Communication, 2020-2022
  - Counterblast, December 2020-May 2022
    Counterblast was a journal edited by professor Sal Fallica of the Media, Culture, and Communications Program and written by faculty and graduate students in that program. The first issue was published in November 2001.
  - Counterblast, August 2020
- RG 26.43. Department of Higher and Postsecondary Education, 2020-ongoing
  - Higher Education Newsletter, May 2020-ongoing
    The Higher Education newsletter (or In the Loop) is the periodic newsletter from the higher education programs at NYU Steinhardt. The newsletter highlights student achievements, event announcements, alumni and faculty updates, and other news from the department.
- RG 27.0. Stern School of Business, the Undergraduate College, 1901-2021
  - Commerce, Accounts, and Finance, 1901-1903 (Box 259, Item 1-2)
  - Elements of Business Finance, 1925 (Box 256, Folder 1-2)
  - Enterprise, 1967-1981 (Box 256, Folder 3-5)
  - Government House Bulletin, 1915 (Box 256, Folder 6)
  - Intercom, 1945-1951 (Box 256, Folder 7-8)
  - Leonard N. Stern School of Business Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for Leonard N. Stern School of Business. Posts relate to admissions, student life, conferences, study abroad, faculty research, student clubs, Entrepreneurs Challenge, social impact events, lecture series on banking, alumni news, Stern history, photographs from events, and other events.
  - Leonard N. Stern School of Business Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter account for Leonard N. Stern School of Business. It contains tweets related to business community news, graduation, New York City highlights, conferences, alumni news, investment fund opportunities, event notices, global economics, #SternLaunch, Future of Finance panel, faculty research, Langone Speaker Series, sharing economy, MBA program, Blankfein at NYU, and other events.
  - Leonard N. Stern School of Business, the Undergraduate College Facebook, May 2014-August 2015
    Facebook page for the Stern undergraduate program. The page contains admissions information, study abroad, activities in New York City, course programs, photographs from events, and student life.
  - Leonard N. Stern School of Business, the Undergraduate College Twitter, May 2014-May 2015
    Twitter account of the New York University Leonard N. Stern School of Business undergraduate college. Contains admissions publicity and information, Stern Day in the Life, Communications Focus Group, Global Leadership Program, International Studies Program, Entrepreneurs Challenge, commencement, free food, clubs, International Business Exchange, and other events.
  - New York University Bulletin, 1943-1961 (Box 256, Folder 9, Box 258, Folder 1-3)
  - SCAF Bulletin, May 1964 (Box 258, Folder 4)
  - Some News from the School of Commerce, 1953 (Box 258, Folder 5)
  - SternBusiness Alumni Magazine, April 2014-April 2019
    STERNBUSINESS Magazine is the alumni magazine of the Stern School of Business. The contents of the magazine includes interviews with business leaders, messages from the dean, faculty appointments, awards, honors, faculty research highlights, alumni news and events, and articles on business affairs. This page contains issues dating back to Fall 1998.
  - SternBusiness Alumni Magazine, May 2019
  - SternBusiness Alumni Magazine, May 2017-May 2021
    STERNBUSINESS Magazine is the alumni magazine of the Stern School of Business. The contents of the magazine includes interviews with business leaders, messages from the dean, faculty appointments, awards, honors, faculty research highlights, alumni news and events, and articles on business affairs. This page contains issues from Fall 1998 to Spring 2018.
  - SternBusiness Alumni Magazine, May 2021
    STERNBUSINESS Magazine is the alumni magazine of the Stern School of Business. The contents of the magazine includes interviews with business leaders, messages from the dean, faculty appointments, awards, honors, faculty research highlights, alumni news and events, donor news, and articles on business affairs. The earliest magazines available from this page start from Spring 2017.
  - Stern Business Report, May 1990 (Box 258, Folder 6)
  - Studies in Business, 1902-1903, 1906 (Box 258, Folder 7-8)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1904-1965 (Box 258, Folder 9-10, Box 260, Folder 1-8, Box 261, Folder 1-7)
  - Promotional Material and Ephemera, 1963-2015 (Box 262, Folder 1-8, Box 263, Folder 1-4)